# **Steve Arrants**

I write. I edit. I help people do things.

**Phone:** 802-881-1726

Address: 137 Country Club Dr E

South Burlington, VT 05403

Website: https://stevearrants.me/
Email: sarrants@qmail.com

Hello! I'm Steve Arrants, a Vermont-based technical writer and editor, content developer, and support specialist. Throughout my career I've investigated, researched, organized, and explained things in accessible and user-friendly ways. I'm not just a technical writer and editor. I also create and manage customer and technical support and knowledge bases for customers and internal audiences in Jira and Confluence. I can provide the same for your company. How? Just ask. Let's have a conversation.

#### SKILLS

Technical Writing, Content Strategy, Content Management, Microsoft Office, Online Help, MadCap Flare, Confluence, JIRA, Camtasia, Git, Markdown, Gatsby

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Jitterbit, Inc.

July 2019 - Present

## Senior Content Developer

Research and write online documentation on iPaaS/SaaS integration software, Jitterbit Harmony. Document on-premises and cloud software and services and produce release notes.

## **Sheridan Journal Services**

Aug 2014 to Jul 2019

## Content Developer and Technical Support Specialist

Create internal and end-user documentation and training for software and services with Madcap Flare and Mkdocs. I also create software simulations and tutorials/videos with TechSmith Camtasia, Articulate. and Adobe products.

Support lead for our SaaS products and manage Confluence and Jira. I also provide documentation and support for other products.

#### **Data Innovations LLC**

Mar 2013 to Jul 2014

#### **Documentation Manager**

Moved print documentation (user guides, training materials) to WebHelp format, giving end users more responsive documentation, better searching, and better discoverability. Single-sourcing WebHelp, print materials, and training guides Directed and managed three writers on a new documentation and publishing process.

### **MBF** Bioscience

Mar 2004 to Mar 2013

### Technical Writer (staff)

Completed move to EPub and Print on Demand, resulting in savings on printing, shipping, storage.

Documented eleven software applications, application notes, and installation and configuration guides for scientific products in print and online formats, utilizing a newly implemented single-source solution. Provided editorial support and direction to Technical Support group and Marketing/Sales.

# **Medical Manager Practice Services (a WebMD Company)**

Sep 2002 to Dec 2003

#### Senior Technical Writer (contract)

Created documentation for FQHC medical practice management software using a single-source publishing system generating print, online, support, and interactive tutorials while meeting all dates and deliverables on time. Oversaw production of all documentation, including marketing and compliance documents. Managed one on-site and two off-site writers.

# iDrive/Anuvio Technologies

Dec 2001 to Jun 2002

### Senior Technical Writer (contract)

Created technical documentation including white papers, programming /API references, and tutorials.

ROIDirect.com Apr 2000 to Nov 2001

#### Writing Manager (staff)

Directed the production of all internal and external documentation for an e-commerce/CRM company.

Managed multiple projects by setting project goals, managing 8 direct reports, establishing deadlines, and monitoring progress. Worked with QA and Development to put into place publishing systems that achieved measurably greater productivity.

**CNET** Feb 1998 to Mar 2000

## Senior Editor (staff)

Created and directed all content, tone, and style for Web site while overseeing all production. Responsible for determining business strategy, hiring, staff development, and management of eight staff and numerous freelancers. Worked with senior editors of other CNET Web sites to schedule and determine content stories and with advertisers and agencies to better position and deliver advertisements. Analyzed Web ratings to determine content for audiences.

**CNET** Feb 1997 to Feb 1998

### Senior Writer and Trainer (contract and staff)

Designed and wrote documentation for internal proprietary software, including standards, practices, and procedures guidelines for CNET sites and CNET partner content. Trained over 300 staff members on internal software and procedures.

# **Applied Business Technology**

Jan 1996 to Feb 1997

## Documentation Manager (staff)

Directed 16 one-site and remote writers and editors, scheduling all documentation from design to distribution. Led a successful documentation redesign for online delivery.

Autodesk Jun 1993 to Dec 1995

# Senior Online Writer (staff)

Wrote end-user product documentation for AutoCAD and associated products.

Directed the design and migration of print documentation to online Help format.

Created online demos and tutorials for end-users.

#### **Reference Software International**

Apr 1992 to May 1993

### Manager of User Documentation (staff)

Supervised and coordinated documentation group (20 direct reports in San Francisco and New Mexico) activities for all end-user and technical documentation on dictionary and grammar products.

## Microsoft Corporation

Dec 1986 to Mar 1992

#### Senior Technical Writer (staff)

Wrote product documentation for end users.

Participated in the design on Microsoft Online Help system and software tools.

Documented programming reference manuals for Microsoft Word, Word for Windows, and other products.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Drew University**

BA, Anthropology and Classical Studies

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Building Your Own Website**

O'Reilly and Associates

## **Designing Windows 95 Help: A Guide to Creating Online Documents**

Que